A Guide to the Papers of Virginius Dabney
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #7690-ak
Papers of Virginius Dabney 1926-1976
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
7690-ak
54 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Gift, 1988 November 21
Container List
- Articles
  - "Virginia" in The American Mercury, 1926 Nov
  - "Intolerance De Luxe in Richmond, Virginia" in Haldeman-Julius Monthly, 1927 May
  - "Fighting the Catholics" in Plain Talk, 1928 May
  - "Americans We Like Governor Byrd of Virginia" in The Nation, 1928 Jun 6
  - "Bishop Cannon Wins An Award" in The Nation, 1929 Apr 17
  - "A Prophet of the New South" in The New York Herald Tribune Magazine, 1929 Aug 25
  - "Negro Barbers in the South" in The Nation, 1930 Jul 16
  - "A New Senator from Virginia?" in The New York Herald Tribune Magazine, 1933 Feb 19
  - "Richmond Starts Its Third Century" in The New York Herald Tribune Magazine, 1933 Sep 17
  - "Secession from Comstockery" in North American Review, 1934 Jan
  - "Reds in Dixie" in Sewanee Review, 1934 Oct-Dec
  - "Edith and Her Pappy" in The New Republic, 1936 Feb 26
  - "Southern Employers and Labor Reform" in The Southern Review, 1936 Autumn
  - "If the South Had Won the War" in The American Mercury, 1936 Oct
  - "The Press and the Elections" in The Public Opinion Quarterly, 1937 Apr
  - "Dixie Rejects Lynching" in The Nation, 1937 Nov 27
  - "Renaissance Below the Potomac" in The New York Times Magazine, 1938 Jul 24
  - "The Ghost Has Not Gone Wet" in Ken, 1938 Aug 25
  - "Shall the South's Poll Tax Go?" in The New York Times Magazine, 1939 Feb 12
  - "Civil Liberties in the South" in Virginia Quarterly Review, 1940 Winter
  - "Standing Firm For Genesis" in The Nation, 1942 Mar 14
  - "The Negro and His Schooling" in The Atlantic, 1942 Apr
  - "Press and Morale" in Saturday Review of Literature, 1942 Jul 4
  - "Nearer and Nearer The Precipice" in The Atlantic, 1943 Jan
  - "Perils in Isolationism - The South's Stake in the War" in St. Louis Times Dispatch, 1943
  - "Southern Progress" in Southern Power and Industry, 1943 Oct
  - "We Are Making Progress" in The Christian Advocate Magazine, 1943 Oct 21
  - "The South Marches On" in Survey Graphic, 1943 Nov
  - "The South and the Fourth Term" in The Economist, 1944 Jun 10
  - "The Argument for a Non-Solid South" in The New York Times Magazine, 1944 Jul 30
  - "What's Wrong With Newspaper Editorials?" in Saturday Review of Literature, 1945 Feb 24
  - "Is the South That Bad?" in The Saturday Review of Literature, 1946 Apr 13
  - "Prohibition's Ghost Walks Again" in Collier's, 1949 Nov 26
  - "What We Think of Senator Byrd's Machine" in Saturday Evening Post, 1950 Jan 7
  - "The Ivy-Covered Fraud" in The Reporter, 1951 Nov 27
  - "Virginia Prefers Byrd" in The Freeman, 1952 Oct 6
  - "Southern Crisis: The Segregation Decision" in The Saturday Evening Post, 1952 Nov 8
  - "He Made the Court Supreme" in The Saturday Evening Post, 1955 Sep 24
  - "School Crisis" in The American, 1956 Aug
  - "The Human Side of Woodrow Wilson" in Virginia Quarterly Review, 1956 Autumn
  - "Jamestown Before the Mayflower" reprinted from The New York Times Magazine, 1957 Sep 29
  - "Virginia's Peaceable, Honorable Stand", 1958 Sep 22
  - "That Mythical First Thanksgiving" in The Saturday Evening Post, 1958 Nov 29
  - "Jack Jouett's Ride" in American Heritage, 1961 Dec
  - "Education in America" in Saturday Review, 1962 Aug 18
  - "What is the GOP Doing in the South" in Harper's Magazine, 1963 May
  - "The Real Reasons for Classroom Cheating" in This Week Magazine The New York Herald Tribune, 1963 May 26
  - "Richmond's Quiet Revolution" in Saturday Review, 1964 Feb 29
  - "Cheating Can Be Stopped" in Saturday Review, 1966 May 21
  - "A Report on the Press in Spain and Portugal" in Saturday Review, 1966 Jul 9
  - "Today's University" in Virginia Journal of Education, 1966 Sep
  - "The Placid Corrida" in Saturday Review, 1966 Sep 10
  - "Richard Heath Dabney: A Memoir" in The Magazine of Albemarle County History, 1975-1976
  - "The American Revolution and Its Meaning For Today", 1976